<p><biblScope>24</biblScope></p>

<p>"The spectators, who had been drawn together, partly by idle curiosity, and partly by a detestation of his supposed crime, retired with tears for his fate, and execrations on his murderers." <persName key="Hall, Francis" from="?" to="1833" role="Lieutenant" ref="http://www.kouroo.info/kouroo/thumbnails/H/ColonelFrancisHall.pdf"> Hall</persName>, pp.433-438</p>

<p>We might fairly challenge the writers of romance to rival this story in depth of interest. We should only weaken its effect by any comments of our own.</p> 
	
<p>The depressed and degraded condition of the Negro slave is communicated, as might be expected, by an al-most infallible contagion, to the whole of the free Black and Coloured population of the <placeName key="United States" ref="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_States"> United States </placeName>. Nor are even those parts of the Union, called, by way of distinction, Free States, in which slavery is abolished by law, exempt from this charge. The curse of slavery pursues the descendants of slaves to the latest generation. <interp key="True - the biggest issue with slavery was that you were hard pressed to find a couple that truly wanted their African-American families to bear any children at all. It was very hard to surpress pregnancy, a lot of happiness is derived from the pleasure love brings, and it does not seem fair to stop the growth of the family on the count of backwards southern agendas. However, at the end of the day, it was still truly believed to be a curse to have African-American blood in your family, it did not stop anyone from placing claim over your soul the moment you were born." n="How Slavery Affected African American Families, Heather Andrea Williams, University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill" cert="high" ref="http://nationalhumanitiescenter.org/tserve/freedom/1609-1865/essays/aafamilies.htm">So long as the slightest tinge of African blood can be discovered to flow in their veins, however professedly liberal the institutions of any particular state may chance to be, the sentence of civil disability and degradation continues in force.</interp> There exists, as Mr. Fearon well expresses it, in all these states, not excepting any, "a penal law deeply written in the minds of the whole White population, which subjects their Coloured fellow-citizens to unconditional contumely and never-ceasing insult. No respectability, however unquestionable; no property, however large; no character, however un-blemished, will gain a man, whose body is, in American estimation, 'cursed with even a twentieth portion of the blood of his African ancestry, admission into society. They are considered as mere Pariahs, as outcasts and vagrants on the face of the earth." These persons, though many of them are possessed of the rights of citizenship, it would be little to say, are not admitted to the exercise of their civil franchises; </p>
	
</body></text></TEI></teiCorpus>